Sex. Violence. Whatever.
The Doom Generation is a comedy, crime, drama film directed by Gregg Araki.
Jordan White and Amy Blue, two troubled teens, pick
up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red.
Together, the threesome embarks on a sex- and violence-filled journey
through a United States of psychos and quickie marts.
Amy Blue, played by Rose McGowan.
Jordan White, played by James Duval.
Xavier Red, played by Johnathon Schaech.
Peanut, played by Cress Williams.
Quickiemart Clerk, played by Dustin Nguyễn.
TV Anchorwoman, played by Lauren Tewes.
The Doom Generation is a 1995 independent black comedy thriller film
co-edited, produced, written, and directed by Gregg Araki.
The film stars James Duval  and Rose McGowan as two troubled teenage lovers who pick up an adolescent drifter,
played by Johnathon Schaech, and embark on a journey full of sex, violence, and convenience stores.
Billed as "A Heterosexual Movie by Gregg Araki", The Doom Generation is the second installment in the director's trilogy known
as the Teenage Apocalypse film trilogy, preceded by Totally F***ed Up (1993) and followed by Nowhere (1997).
The characters of Amy Blue and Jordan White are based on
the Mark Beyer comic strip Amy and Jordan.
Araki's major film debut, shooting primarily took place at night during
January 1994 in Los Angeles on a budget of $800,000.
The crew avoided well known landmarks and shot in undeveloped
areas of urban sprawl to give an apocalyptic feel.
The budget allowed Araki to hire professional crew, making it
the first of his films not shot by himself.
The film premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on January 26, 1995.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
During the press screening, many critics left.
However, at the San Francisco International Film Festival (SFIFF), it received
critical acclaim, most proclaiming it as Araki's breakthrough.
Distributed by Trimark Pictures, it was released in
the United States on October 27, 1995.
While not a financial success, earning only $284,785 at the box office, McGowan was
nominated for Best Debut Performance at the 11th Independent Spirit Awards.
The film explores themes of friendship, california, robbery, nazi, nihilism.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending and emotional.